good morning everyone welcome to the
session on aesthetic dentistry
uh from today we are going to start off
with the posterior aesthetic procedures
uh which includes the class 1 and class
2 and class six
lesions
so we are going to discuss
all these individual procedures
separately
as with any therapeutic treatment proper
diagnosis should be attempted before any
course of treatment
although the etiology of a specific
discoloration may be difficult to
recognize as we discussed in our
previous session
we have
various types of
treatment modalities which depends on
conservative aesthetic procedures as
well as non-conservative aesthetic
procedures including the conservative
static procedures we discussed two
categories of treatment modalities
number one is the non-invasive treatment
procedure in which we are not supposed
to use any high speed turbine but rather
it's by definition is a non-invasive
type of treatment
and then followed by minimally invasive
in which we are reducing the tooth
structure in microns let's say between
300 to 400 microns so these kind of
procedures we call it as minimally
invasive conservative aesthetic
procedures
so including the invasive static
we are going to address all these
clinical conditions individually
talking about
the indications of class 1 composite
restoration there are some absolute
indications whenever doing an occlusal
composite restoration
small and moderate restorations
preferably with enamel margins
most premolars or molar restorations
particularly when aesthetics is
considered
a restoration that does not provide
all of the occlusal contacts
or a restoration that does not have any
occlusal contacts
a restoration that can be appropriately
isolated during the procedure
some restorations that may serve as
foundations for crowns or core buildup
some very large restorations that are
used to strengthen the remaining or
weakened structure
uh in situations when whenever there is
some economic concern with the patient
when talking about the contraindications
of the composite restoration when the
operating site cannot be properly
isolated okay the isolation is the most
important part of any composite
restoration whenever there is some kind
of
heavy occlusal stresses in patients with
parafunctional habits
with when there is
all the occlusal contacts are only in
the compost composites
and poor oral hygiene is also one of the
contraindications of using composite
restorations
when
uh when talking
when talking about the advantages of
composite restoration we know that
uh all composite restorations are
aesthetically pleasing our tooth colored
respiratory material and uh there is
conservative tooth structure removal we
do not remove
with the concept in mind
that extension for prevention which was
described by gv black
rather we just remove the lesion part
only it's comparatively easier and less
complex to preparation it provides
insulation decreases the micro leakage
and there are some added benefits of the
bonding system itself
for example decrease in recurrent
carries decrease in post-operative
sensitivity increase in retention and
increase in the strength of the
remaining third structure
when talking about the disadvantages the
disadvantages are mostly related to the
material
or
when if you are not using a recommended
material there is a greater localized
wear
there if you are not using in the
described manner there will be some
polymerization shrinkage effects
uh if the material is not good there
could be some linear coefficient of
thermal expansion and the
biocompatibility including this gma of
some components is unknown
it requires more time to place as
compared to amalgam it is more technique
sensitive
you need etching priming and adhesive
placements
inserting the composites developing the
proximal contacts finishing and
polishing and in comparison to amalgam
it is expensive
okay let's discuss with the clinical
techniques of class one composite
restoration
uh the initial clinical procedure the
first and the most important step is the
shade selection the shade of the tooth
should be determined before the teeth
are subjected to any prolonged drying
because dehydrated teeth become lighter
brighter in shade as well as they
decrease in translucency
minor or no truth preparation
may be necessary to clean the operating
site with slurry of pumice to remove
the biofilm plaque particles and
superficial stains and sometimes the
calculus removal is also important
knowing the prep
of the occlusal relationship is
paramount for optimum restoration
after that we provide the local
anesthesia why because
it's more pleasant and uninterrupted
procedure
and there is a marked reduction in
salivation as well
isolation is extremely important for a
successful composite restoration
although with cotton rolls and other
means of indirect isolation a composite
restoration can be profound but it is
highly unpredictable
the next part comes with the truth
preparation
in which we are only going to remove the
faulty tooth structure
not extension for the prevention as givi
black described
and we also create a convenience form in
order to
place the composite in more recommended
fashion
the retention of the composite
restoration is always obtained with the
help of bonding
guys let's discuss a clinical case of
class 1 composite restoration
as you see that it's lowered mandibular
molar
the main complaint of the patient was
that he is unable to masticate with that
tooth and he is true in that regarding
that thing because the occlusion is flat
and
you know that in natural motors
occlusion is never be a flat thing to
always have uh curse and fissures in the
grooves that helps in mastications so we
need to restore that tooth as natural as
possible so that patient can masticate
as we are doing with our natural
dentitions
uh guys
as you know that before start of the
procedures we need to record the
occlusions as patient occlusion has been
changed by a previous dentist so
it might be possible that to
maintain
the natural occlusion uh would be
difficult uh in such in such cases so
first of all we have to record uh the
occlusal spots where a patient actually
masticate and that can be done with the
help of an articulating paper and
remember that uh to recall these records
we need to photograph it so that when we
uh just doing uh the occlusion in the
final in the final thing so we know how
uh to maintain all these previous
records in the final restoration so this
thing is very important so you have to
know where the masticatory spots are
coming so it will help you a lot in the
final adjustment of the occlusions
then the thing come is uh which bear we
have to use to make a cavity um it's
it's a round bear obviously round bear
but it can be a diamond it can be a
carbide so it depends on the preference
but my recommendation is for the initial
for the beginners that you must use a
round diamond because it is easy to
control it and
easy to have a good grip on that thing
but in carbides you can grind the tooth
in a minute so try to get some uh
training with the carbide then use it in
your cavity preparations but for that
thing you can use a round diamond uh
right now so it's a good bear
uh then the next thing is to prepare a
cavity and
in that case i used a round diamond
uh and a small bur i used uh with a with
air and water spray and why in water
spray so that we don't need to dry the
dentine as dentine has a lot of water
and has collagen uh has a lot of intent
in tubules as well so once you dry it
dentin throw away all the water and that
leads to sensitivity and the most
frequent complaint of the patients with
the composite is sensitivity post-op
sensitivity so that's how we can
manage uh this problem so we have to we
don't have to cut the tooth in a dry
situation we have always used air and
water spray so that we try to cool the
denting so water remains in its position
then come towards the etching
as you know that enamel is a different
substrate and then t needs a different
substrate so we need a separate systems
for both of them
as enamel is more mineralized has less
water has no collagen
so we use a total edge it's a strongest
acid and we can wash and dry the enamel
there is no problem with that but when
comes towards the dentine then teen has
a lot of water and the collagen so we
don't need to dry it we need such a
system that can actually uh etch and
bond it and don't need to wash and dry
it for that thing self edge is the best
thing uh in that dentine etching and the
bonding and it's also a system that
limits basically post-op sensitivity
there is no post-op sensitivity when you
use selfish system so guys total edge
for the enamel and self edge for the
denting and the time is about 20 seconds
and total as you know 37 phosphoric acid
is a very common thing it's available in
the market it's the most common thing
you can find in any clinic
so uh then you have to apply the
adhesive as in self etch with the accent
and the bond in one tube but in total
edge you need a separate adhesive system
uh when you are doing etching and
wanting to enamel so you can use self
etch
in enamel after doing a total edge
so the important thing is that when you
apply it as if you have to apply two to
three coats so that it can
cover all the dentin tubules it can
basically lubricate all the denting and
there is no area left where the adhesive
is not
going there so you have to follow it
then you cure it for about 20 seconds
and
before curing you need to dry it a bit
so that you have very thin layer deposit
on the tooth surface
then the most important thing is how to
fill the box
before
going to make occlusion
the best thing in this regard is you
have to apply a flowable about 1mm
increment at the base why flavor because
it can flow everywhere it can adapt well
and you can see in the picture uh that
there is no voids in the bubbles and
there is no shrinkage there's no
debonding you can evaluate everywhere so
then you have to build the remaining box
of the cavity in two millimeter
increments
the the basic purpose of doing two
millimeter increments is to avoid
polymerization shrinkage
and guys when you try to cure it you
always increase the intensity of light
with the passage of the time because if
you if you use a high uh curing light
high intensity during light it will lead
to shrinkage it will lead to sensitivity
but once you use a curing light that
increase intensity step wise so you can
avoid the polymerization shrinkage and
the post-op sensitivity as well
so in that picture you can visualize
when you see your restorations from the
lateral view that there is no gap there
is no shrinkage and it adapts well when
you have such a beautiful adapted
restorations then your patients never
complain about sensitivity and never
complain about dislodgement of the
filling so you have to
do this thing but for that you need a
magnifications what we're using in
clinics we don't have magnification so
we have no idea where the composite is
going where the flowable is going so you
need a magnification for that you need a
training with a magnifying lobes and
microscope etc
then we this is the pizza technique
basically and as we know as we know the
pizza there are a lot of slices in the
pizza but they're equal in sizes so uh
the way we are going to build over this
molar in a pizza way but the slices in
the molar is not similar god has created
the molars in different slices every
cusp has a different mass different size
different volume and different
morphology so first of all you have to
read the morphology then you can mimic
in your restorations
uh in like in mandibular molar you have
five cusps the biggest one is a
mesobuckle
and then you have a mesiolingual then
you have a distrolingual then you have
dystrobucker and then you have a distal
the most easiest cast to model is a
mesiobuccal one
keeping the anatomical landmarks in mind
you just take an increment of the
composite and then place it along the
cusp and model it with a with your
spatula and you can use a bit of
modeling liquid so you can adapt
the cusp in a good way but don't
increase the volume
as did in the morphology
it's the most uniform and most easiest
class to model but we have to study the
anatomy before doing this
then the next curve distro buckle cusp
it has a proper shape it's a triangular
shape so you cannot adapt it in a
rectangular way so
the limits of the cusp you have to keep
in mind you cannot extend
the composite or the curves to the
neighboring ones you have to maintain
the margins and that's only possible
with the proper training and
don't have to over contour it you have
to align it along the walls
never above the walls you can see the
margins are very clear here there is no
overhanging composite so you keep in
mind and
then you can do that
then uh the next is a mesolingual and
disto lingual both cars are modeled at
the same time and but
that's only possible if you have a grip
on that thing but for the beginners you
have to do in a step wise
so uh and then you have to cure it
obviously every increment need at least
20 second cure with your light cure
machine so cure it properly you can over
cure it even there's no problem with
that there's no harm in that
so uh the only thing is that the curing
light
should never touch the crucial surface
it's a bit away from the cool surface
because it can contaminate the occlusion
it can contaminate the light as well so
and the efficiency of the light will be
decreased in in after that procedures
because you're doing a lot of things in
clinics
and then you complete the modeling the
distal cost is the easiest cause it's
the smallest cause so you can complete
the modeling and then you can if you
evaluate that there's five cuts there
and every cusp has the morphology that
we are studied in our dynamic books so
uh follow these things and do that
things but after reading uh the exact
the morphology and the volume of the
curves
then uh the next thing is finishing and
the polishing after doing the
restorations the most important thing is
how to finish and polish it because uh
finishing and polishing without
finishing and polishing your
restorations cannot live much longer and
it can attract the strain and the food
can deposit over there and at the end
you will end into discolorations and the
poor restorations and restoration will
go away so finishing and polishing is a
very important and mandatory step and
for that you also need your training but
i'm right now i'm telling you that for
the external services of the finishing
you need a desk here that's a coarse
disc to remove the excess composite over
the custard margins because if you don't
remove it the patient might have uh the
bad inclusions he can complain that a
queen is not right he cannot masticate
and if he goes home with that inclusion
with overhanging restorations then the
next day he will come with the pain so
you have to finish the excessive
composite on the walls and everywhere
then the internal surfaces of the
restorations is finished with the
finishing diamond
and the very in a very light and gentle
way you don't need to trim it you have
just to move it in a very slow speed
just to remove the over hanging
composites there so and you can do it in
a dry situation there's no because in a
dry way if you do it you can visualize
if you use a water here
the details might be lost and you might
make some things that need to be removed
then before polishing uh before
polishing and you you have to wash all
the debris if you don't wash it
these debris can accumulate
in the fissures and then it will just uh
make a bad uh color to the restoration
so you have to wash it first
i don't see uh
how the restoration looks beautiful
after finishing even just after
finishing because you have a very
uniform and smooth surface and there is
no roughness there so once you have such
surface
you will have a very beautiful polishing
and this polishing will never go away if
you have such a finished and smooth
surface
then before polishing you need a
polishing paste you can use the diamond
polishing paste and you can use whatever
you have in the clinic but important
thing you polish it just apply a bit of
it on the tooth surface and spread it
with a micro brush and then take a
polishing brush like goat wheel or some
other and then just polish it so
uh this polishing just make your uh
restoration
smooth and shiny and gives the
restriction a brilliant surface so not
even bacteria can
adapt to that finish and polish surface
so try to the polishing us
then after completing all the procedures
you can visualize the first of all
crucial contacts we recorded the same
algorithal context in the previous
initial picture so you can see the same
occlusal context we have in the final
picture it means
we know how to record the previous
context and follow these contexts in the
post picture that is only possible if
you have a documented record and that is
with the photographs so take the
photographs and follow these uh
photographic
marks in the final
adjustment of the occlusions and about
the tenths you know ninety percent of
the cases of the fissure have a strain
fissures so we just apply the tints here
to make that molar as natural as human
dentitions because yes in few cases you
don't see strain fissures but 90 percent
of cases there are strain fissures and
we have done a lot of molars in clinical
practice and every molar is stained
except the few ones so some patients ask
me some doctors ask me sir that looks
very bad because you are just putting a
brown tent in a fish it looks bad but
and might be we drill it we consider it
as a carries but it's not a carries it's
just a stained fissure and if you have
an experience you cannot uh make it
curious so curious legends looks
different so that's why otherwise there
is no benefit of doing sustaining
so in this image
we can see a previously placed amalgam
restoration within creeped
margins associated with the secondary
carries
uh you can also see the initial patent
facial religion on the distal surface
and then secondary region around the
amalgam
in such leans
as you see that amalgam is looking worse
in uh
its appearance
and
also the anatomy has not been
goodly captured
uh isolation is the first step
as you can see the rubber dam is applied
and the diamond version is seen very
beautiful in this without isolation we
cannot go with some excellent
restorations in the modern era of
dentistry
uh after preparing the cavity the
difference between the preparation of
amalgam and the composite is that in an
algorithm we need specific dapps special
specific axial taps
line angles straight floor but with
composites we usually don't need any
such preparation because the process of
bonding is been accomplished as a
different step
so
we just need to remove the carriage
legion with a round bar or a carbide bar
starting specifically with a high speed
and ending with the slow speed handpiece
but that will control the cavity
preparation
so this is the modeling
the modeling include
as doctors here very well explained the
different welding steps like pizza
technique
incremental technique and the successive
cusp build up technique
you have to build the cusp step by step
and the successive cusp built up
technique in the incremental technique
you layered it within increments
this is the post of occlusal records
to see
either the restoration is high or it's
an inclusion by changing the slide spots
you can change and you can play with the
occlusion of the patient
so by maintaining these spots well in
occlusion the patient can utilize his
teeth in the pattern he was used using
previously
any spot is not a high spot you can see
a lot of marks in the peg but these are
not the high spot
a high spot is basically a bull eye mark
that seems to be shiny in the middle and
from the periphery it's been well
colored by the type of articulating
paper we are using
so every spot is not a high spot to
check your high spot
usually you're supposed to check your
articulating paper once you include the
patient's teeth
the articulating paper should have been
pierced from a center and you can see a
shining spot on the patient teeth
and this is a controlled photograph
after a week time
when the teeth is well hydrated you can
see there's ideal color matching and the
ideal shade is there ideal sculpting is
there and the patient is well happy with
this type of restoration
looking for another case
uh in which we are going to see the
initial lesion
as you can see there is break in the
integrity of the enamel and the legion
is spreading in towards the dega level
uh by looking it seems to be a very uh
small cavity but remember the number
legends are usually a v-shaped cavity
with a
v-shaped neck on the closest surface and
the broad base towards the dej when you
start removing such cavities they're
gonna grow bigger
application of the rubber dam again
see the version of the rubber dam it's
beautiful
no seepage of saliva can be seen if you
apply the rubber diamond well go
here we'll talk about the disclosing
dies
a disclosing die is an agent which when
applied to a tooth
structure
making anything visible that is foreign
matter on the tooth structure
how it works the mechanism of action of
disclosing agent is that it worked by
changing the color of the dental plaque
to that it contrasts with the white
tooth structure
dental plaque
has the ability to retain a large number
of dye substances which can be used for
the disclosing purposes
this property is related to the
interaction because of the polarity
difference between the components of the
plaque and the dyes
the particles are bonded to the surface
by electrostatic interactions proteins
and hydrogen bonds like polystyrites
there are different dyes
like we use in dentistry are from iodine
preparations like fast green
erythrocene basic fluorescent
and bismarck brown and there are many
others
remember at this point that when we are
ever applying the disclosing dye we are
supposed to apply it for 10 seconds
and then wash it thoroughly
after washing if the dye retains in
areas these areas are meant to be
curious so you're supposed to clean this
area very cautionary very uh under
observation so that we're going to
remove the further area remove these
areas and with the die stick and then
start filling
so here's the sculpting uh of the mar
restoration cast two cusps built up you
can see the pits and the fissures and
every cusp has been defined beautifully
separately
after the removal of the rubber dam see
the occlusal spots
these occlusal spots are mandatory to
check for the occlusion remember the
functional cusp of the lowers are the
buckles and
for the uppers upper zero parallels the
end they retain the the
functional curve will retain the
vertical dimensions of the face
let's move towards the discussion what
we have already discussed
so i have a very
simple question
why class one lesions are more common
uh because the class one lesion is on
the closer surface of the mandible or
molars
so there are the pectin fissures that
are the nikai for any
external particles that can be attracted
with that
so what do you suggest doctors here do
all the pets and fishers are the
knackers no dr delaware
you have seen a lot of mandibular motors
in the maxillary motors the pitch and
fissures they are smooth and
self-cleansable
so it's not necessary that every every
patient has class one carries only those
patients who have deep pelts in the
fissures where there is chances of food
accumulation you mean known police
surface yes
when the lobes are unable to join
together so in those cases there are
more chances of class one and and the
third thing is very important thing
because it's a surface where the patient
try to masticate
so it's it's a surface where your brush
bristles cannot reach the deep bits and
features so this is also a factor so
hope we can prevent the class 1 lesions
to be formed over kashif uh pits and
fissure sealants or we can do some
enantioplasty so we can
make themselves make themselves
cleanable if the food is getting
stagnated on the surface the carious
lesion will start if it is easily
cleaned
there will be no cases
throw some light on an amyloplasty what
is that possible blue plastic basically
has been done with smaller strong birds
like one by 16 rounder to make the area
uh self-cleanable basically these pits
and fissures are like the valleys
between the mountains and these valleys
does accumulates a lot of materials from
the food particles and any other
chromogens in the diet particles so we
shall make them self-cleanable so it's a
preventive procedure
exactly
so the next question is
what is the pathogenesis of class one
lesion
how the class one lesion starts we know
that uh inside these non-polar fissures
there is some food is accumulating
leading to bacterial biofilm and which
is producing the lactic acid by which
the the mineral part is demineralizing
so beyond that what is the pathogenesis
what happens the histopathology of uh
the class one
kds or enamel queries is divided into
different zones like translucent zone
darker zone body of lyon and the surface
league depending upon the pore size of
the enamel as the pore size increases as
we go deeper the pore size increases and
the lesions get gross
moving to another question dr zuhair
what is kerry's disclosing die you know
it was a very common practice that we
always remove the infected and effective
affected part of the carries by just
holding a bur and try to remove
the soft carries and even with the
removal of soft carries we remove the
affected zone as when so the case is
closing die is not a recent innovation
it's a die available in the market you
just put it into your tooth surface
where you want to remove the carries and
the best thing about dye is it just
stained the infected part the denatured
collagen and it's paired the affected
one where collagen is intact it comes in
pink color it comes in green color it
comes in blue colors whatever the color
is available in the market uh
uh in superficial lesions it's important
that we can use any color um
if we can use pink or red color it can
be used in the superficial zone but not
in the deep zones because it's going to
be very difficult to discriminate
between the purple exposure
and the dye so it is important that if
we are going to use the disclosing dye
we use
blue or green dye in the deep carious
lesion to discriminate between the
purple exposure yes and
the mode of action is that it works by
the polarity difference between the
components of the plaques and the dyes
because anything that accumulates on the
white surface shows us the polarity
difference once we use the disclosing
dyes yes and the procedure of
application is you just take a micro
brush and put some dye in the tooth
surface and wait for 20 seconds and then
wash it away
the area where
where the stain is you have to remove
that thing but the area where there is
no stain that's affected part that can
be mineralized so kashif can you name
few of the dyes we used as a carriage
disclosing dyes uh we have
bromine we have erythrosan and we have a
frost green
these are the three dyes which are
available
another is like bismarck brown and
merburim and basic fusion and that is
available in the market with the brand
name of gary's detector carries detector
yes you can ask your technician to buy
that thing
so the next question is what are the
differences between amalgam and
composite earth preparation
there is nothing similar between amalgam
and the composite amalgam is aggressive
material where you need a proper depth
and proper width of the shape of the
cavity you just remove the sound to
structure to get some undercuts but in
composite you don't need all these
things you just need to remove the
carries and we just bond the composite
so can we say doctors
we use an algorithm for
for extension for prevention
and we use composites
for prevention from extension yes yes
you can you're right you're right
because uh we are only removing the
fault
uh for amalgam we need a strict and
specific geometry of the dimensions like
the depth if the depth is less than two
millimeter amalgam is not going to
survive but if we talk about the
resistance form the resistance form is
universal for any material but whenever
we are talking about the retention form
we know that the composite is being
retained with the help of adhesive
system
not with the undercuts so we do not
provide any undercuts in composite
restoration
so amalgam is a macro mechanically
retained material and the composite is a
micro mechanical
plus chemical plus chemical bonded
material and the last important thing is
color of the composite amalgam is a
silver dark in color and composite is
white and we have to condense the like
with a proper force like copper force
you can feel it you can feel it and with
composure you just have to pack back and
pack and just sculpt the way you want
so the next question is which burr is
recommended when doing a composite
restoration
basically we use a rounder that can be a
diamond that can be a carbide
i discussed in the lecture previous
slides that to control a carbide is a
difficult thing but to control the
diamond is an easiest thing
it means you can use the carbides when
you have a proper training on that shift
do you think that there is any advantage
of using a diamond bird at the start of
the preparation
or the carbides if we are in on the
superficial zone i think diamonds are
more recommended because they produce a
lot of smear layer hence they are
producing smear plug
but when we whenever we are in the deep
carious lesion uh we need to have some
carbide burs so that we can easily scoop
away from all uh
the the if we have suitable time we
should move and start our preparation
with a high speed and at the end using a
slow slow speed with a carbide bar that
can control our preparation exactly
you're right all right
uh moving towards the uh etching and
bonding technique which is the most uh
ideal for is it a total edge self-hatch
or selective edge which is best for
classroom composite restoration
for enamel uh we discussed already that
an aml is a highly mineralized structure
for that we need a strongest asset and
that is that that is it is only
available in the form of total h and
selective edge
selective h means we just etch the
enamel and then we need a separate
system for dentine and that is self-edge
so for enamel selective edge and for
dentine self edge
as doctors are here experience well
about the total edge so enamel is the
hardest layer so what etching is doing
is just raising the surface area it
decreasing the surface tension so that
the bonding agent will fit properly
and
the ideal standard for enamel generation
is four to fifth generation
and the sulfatch is seven and eight
generations coming in single bottle that
is difficult to handle because of the
concentration of the water and its shelf
life is also a problem so please add
something uh sixth generation is also
self-action and which uh separate the
primer itself is uh uh acidic so we
don't need any separate action in the
sixth generation so it's advisable that
whenever we are dealing with dentine
it's
important that we should use the
self-etch method rather than total edge
otherwise the totalized one will dry the
surface the collagen will collapse and
the total light system also removes all
the smear plug completely which leads to
post-op sensitivity
yes
uh the final question is why composites
tend to shrink more in class one cavity
configuration
since we know that we discussed in the
configuration factor or the c factor
that the class one has the highest c
factor why because we have multiple
bonded walls and how what is the
mechanism of the shrinkage of composite
it always shrinks from bonded to
unbonded surface so if we have more
bonded surfaces there is a greater
tendency of composite shrinkage to
overcome this as you have seen during
the description of dr zuhair he used a
flowable flowable time to shrink more
but it doesn't
exert too much force on the surface so
it can easily adopt on the immediate uh
surface of the tooth structure on top of
it we can use any packable composites so
the configuration factor is most
important and it is determined by the
cavity
the class one we can use pre-polymerized
resins we can use salary and based
composites and we can also use uh the
snowplow technique like uh kashif
explained like use the flower in the
base and then pack the packable in that
so that it can go into the voids
at the end of the lecture i want to say
that this lecture is a team effort i am
very thankful to dr kashif and dr time
dr lover for their valuable time
and the hope we will continue the same
pattern in our future lectures
and we try to make it interactive
anybody can give the lecture but via
this interaction we can clear a lot of
queries which come into your mind free
hand whenever you listen the lecture you
will be clearing a lot of queries that's
coming in your mind
two are better than one and three are
better than two have a good time